You turned down the scholarship
because you needed to work
to help your father,
who if I'm not mistaken had a heart problem.
Sadly, an intelligent,
hardworking and good student
like you is not in school.
I have a proposal for you.
You can still cook for us to help your family
but now you have the option
to study in GU if you want.
You might exhaust yourself
and won't have time for yourself.
No, don't worry. I can handle that.
Me of all people,
I inherited your good traits.
Just make sure that you can
take care of yourself.
Yes, Mother.
You don't have to worry because I can do this.
Isn't Nero okay with you?
He always gives me dagger looks.
He only looks mad, but he's okay with you.
As a matter of fact,
he's one of your biggest defenders
here in the mansion.
It's also not a stretch to say
that because of Nero up to now,
you're still the cook for the Ferells.
Sorry, Nero for judging you.
You're okay even if you're a bit weird.
Okay, promise, I will not judge you again.
Well then let me take this opportunity
to tell you
that Don Ferell and I talked already
about sending you to school.
I was planning to talk to you.
I just want to let you know
that even though I'll be going to GU,
I will not neglect my work here.
Very good then,
I guess we won't have a problem.
Nero?
He's early.
Where is he going?
Should I confront him tomorrow?
But... it looks like DJ Acapulco is right.
I should give him the time and space...
until he is ready to admit his true feelings.
Wow, feelings, you assume too much Florence.
Who do you think you are, Jennilyn Mercado?
Are you that beautiful for him
to have secret feelings for you?
Wow, then.
You think you're...
But what will I wear tomorrow?
A t-shirt?
Flower skirt?
This one?
Why are you thinking, Florence?
You're not going on a date with Nero.
You'll just go to the farm.
Why are you so concerned about your outfit?
What's happening to you, Florence?
Just be yourself.
Let's play some music.
Do you want to sing?
I sing out of tune.
It's not important if you're in tune or not.
What's important is...
you're beautiful.
Let's go.
Do I look okay?
I think I'm overdressed.
What are you doing there? Let's go.
Hurry up.
Coming, sir.
What are you waiting for?
Let's go.
Seat belt.
It's so quiet.
Let's play some music.
Don't touch any part of my car.
Okay.
So, Nero, how are you?
I was thinking
I'll share some things about myself,
well, you know, we're in the same house
so it's better that you know
the people you're with.
So, let's start with your favorite color.
As for me, my favorite color is blue.
I bet you think it's pink
like all the girls out there.
Well, pink is also okay
but the color blue puts me in a better mood.
Oh my, he doesn't even bother
to make small talk.
If you think that I will stop,
well, you're wrong.
Do you like K-Pop?
I think you're into K-Pop.
I'm starting to like K-Pop.
I'm excited about
the 4th Generation of K-Pop,
but I will always be a Uaena by heart.
IU will always be my bias,
that's why it's one of my dreams
to travel to Seoul,
and I will hang out in Myeongdong
and I will indulge myself non-stop
in the street food of Korea.
It's so delicious. The best!
Tteokbokki, soondae, mandu!
That's one of my bucket list!
How about you, what's your food trip like?
Do you have a favorite food?
Let me guess.
I'm not a judgmental person
but if I were to judge you,
I think your favorite food is Sinigang.
I'm good, right?
You're so sour, that's why.
Or grapes?
Are you fond of grapes?
How about bananas?
There's saba, senyorita, lakatan?
Which one is your preference?
Santol? Mangoes?
Buko? Buko Pie!
How about tomatoes?
Yup, contrary to the popular belief,
tomatoes are fruits too.
See, your time is not wasted
while hanging out with me
because we're doing
an educational program today.
How about you?
When did you learn how to drive?
Why did we stop?
Are we here already?
Why did you put down the roof?
Relax, Florence, maybe Nero is the shy type,
so find a way
so he can be comfortable with you.
So he can tell you the truth
instead of using his doves.
Mama Nida.
- Nero!
- Papa Dante...
- I miss you.
- Nero.
Nero, is that you?
- Papa Dante.
- Son...
How are you?
We miss you too.
We thought you won't visit us here.
Is that possible?
And Nero, who are you with?
Me?
Florence Dela Cruz,
I'm the current cook in their mansion.
Wow, they hired someone young
to cook in the mansion.
No, they used to hire professionals,
but they don't have a choice
because no one wants to cook for them.
Is that so?
I'm Nida by the way,
and this is my husband, Dante.
I already spoke to Don Ferell.
It seems he's so excited about the chopsuey
you're about to cook.
That only means one thing.
Before you can get his trust,
you should be a superb cook.
True, and I'll claim that
because with all the problems on this earth,
we shouldn't add false humility to it.
That's right.
Correct, this kid has a point.
- I miss you so much.
- I miss you too.
How are you doing, Son?
I'm doing okay, of course,
just like Papa Dante.
See, I told you.
And you believe him?
Of course, his roots are here.
- I don't know about you.
- Yes.
This area, Nero, is where your grandpa
wants to plant strawberries.
The seeds are scheduled to arrive next month.
Why don't you join us in planting them?'
Okay, Papa Dante.
I will tell grandpa.
Hey, you were quick.
This kid is so good.
She's very good at gauging vegetables.
What Ms. Serafica said is right,
this kid is good.
Really?
Let's try.
Why did you choose this?
Why this broccoli?
Are you going to test me, Papa Dante?
That's just basic, Papa Dante.
Of course, just based on the color,
you should know right away.
There shouldn't be any brown or yellow spots.
When it comes to the stem,
there shouldn't be any patches
of black or white.
And when it comes to the cabbages,
the head must be dense and firm.
And the leaves should be crispy.
With the bell pepper...
You're knowledgeable about vegetables.
How about fruits?
When it comes to fruits,
it depends on the type of fruit.
There are different ways to gauge them
but usually, with just the color,
you'd be able to know right away.
Another way also is the texture
like the bananas and mangoes.
Just by checking the texture,
you'd know if it's fresh or not.
There are factors that you'd know right away.
You can also check its scent.
Well, both fresh fruits
and not-so-fresh fruits can smell good
but it really smells different
if the fruits are so fresh.
But sometimes,
there are fruits that you can't gauge
just by their outside appearances,
like watermelon and coconut.
Sometimes, no matter how good
they look on the outside,
when you check the inside,
it's not good anymore.
- It's no longer fresh.
- That's right.
So what you have to do is
knock on it so you'd know
if it's fresh or not.
So you'd know the truth.
Just like gauging the character of a person.
That's true.
- That's true, right?
- Yes.
Because my mother told me, very often,
the outside appearance of a person
is different from their character.
So if you want to know them very well,
you should knock on their hearts.
Cheers?
Cheers.
Dad, is this one of your life lessons?
How to knock at someone's heart?
Just like this?
Go ahead, son,
laugh at me but someday,
the time will come when you will say,
"Dad is right".
Because believe it or not...
you'll only know a person
if you know what's inside of them.
- Dad,
- It's good.
I believe in what you're saying.
My only question is
how do you knock on someone's heart?
That's correct.
Florence, my child.
Let me ask you.
What if the person whose heart
you're knocking to
refuses to let you in his life?
That's not possible.
What if he really refused to let you in?
I will just keep on knocking...
Knock, knock, knock, until he opens the door.
If he doesn't want to open the door,
I'll destroy it.
If I need to sneak into the sidelines
or peep out the window so he'd let me in,
I'll do it.
If I need to shout, I will shout.
Hey, let me in your heart!
- Hey, let her in your heart!
- Hey, let me in your heart!
Let me in for the kind of beauty
you're not expecting,
just like me.
I'm sure he'll let you in.
- Really?
- Yes.
- Let her in your heart!
- Let me in you heart!
I don't know if he will let you in with that.
What's his problem?
Cheers?
Cheers.
Dad, is this one of your life lessons?
How to knock at someone's heart?
Just like this?
Go ahead, son, laugh at me,
but someday the time will come
when you will say,
"Dad is right".
Because believe it or not...
you'll only know a person
if you know what's inside of them.
- Dad,
- It's good.
I believe in what you're saying.
My only question is
how do you knock on someone's heart?
Know the story of their life.
Listen without mocking or judgment.
And put yourself in their situation.
Okay, but Dad,
there won't come a time
when someone will knock at my heart,
because I will be the one
to knock at someone else's heart
when I start courting.
You're full of foolishness.
But Dad, was it you
who knocked at Mom's heart?
With your mom, it's the opposite.
It was her who first knocked at my heart.
- Really?
- Yes.
Wow.
Mom is aggressive.
She made the first move.
Even the second and third moves.
Wait, she might hear me.
But you know, son,
I wish the time would never come
when you'd feel that something
is lacking in your life.
But when that day comes...
I hope you'll meet someone
who will knock on your heart.
That's my prayer.
And so, let her in.
So she would know the real you.
And for you to realize that
nothing is lacking with you.
There's a big space in the heart to love.
Hand me one more.
This is your third.
Rambutan.
What?
You're asking me
what's my favorite fruit, right?
It's rambutan.
My favorite...
because it tastes like a kiss.
Does rambutan taste like a kiss?
Do you want to taste...
the rambutan?
The rambutan tastes sweet.
What's with you, Florencia?
What kind of imagination is that?
Nero just told you his favorite fruit,
and now you had a dream like that?
What's the taste of the kiss of the rambutan?
Most likely it tastes like rambutan, but...
is it sweeter?
It depends on the rambutan.
Son of the rambutan!
- Grandpa Garp?
- Yes.
Why are you here?
I'm eating leftover chopsuey. It's delicious.
Just like I imagined.
Oh thanks, by the way,
you granted my request.
You're welcome, but Grandpa Garp...
why are you eating in the dark?
I can't find the switch.
I don't want to disturb you.
That's okay. The switch is over there.
Next time you get hungry around this time,
just call me.
Duly noted.
I also have one request.
Can you please make me a cup of coffee?
Sure, but is it okay with you
if I make a Cafe-ala-Florencia for you?
Yeah, sure.
What's that?
I'm sorry, Dad.
I miss you so much.
I miss you.
By the way...
how was your trip to the farm?
How's Nero?
With the 100 questions I asked him,
he answered one question,
so, it's not so bad.
And somehow he spoke.
He's really like that.
You know, with this trip,
I was hoping he would socialize with you.
Well, he's okay with Mr. Dante and Ms. Nida,
but he was ignoring me a bit.
By the way, I have a question if it's okay.
Okay, sure.
Did something happen to Nero?
Why did he become like that?
You know, Nero only became like that
ever since his father died.
I'm sorry I made you remember
that painful memory.
No, don't be sorry.
After all, it's been three years.
My son did not enjoy a luxurious life.
He and his wife, Eliza,
were doctors to the barrios.
That's where they formed their family...
in Barrio Masagana, in Santa Rita.
Nero grew up in the province,
so he's more of a provincial guy.
Nero loves his father so much.
You take this once a day.
And this too, okay?
Here.
Thank you.
Are you okay, son?
I want to go home now.
There are a few patients left.
Your mom and I won't be long.
I thought we'll just be here
for a short time.
I promised Troy that we'll line up
for the opening of Infinity Wars.
I shouldn't have joined you
if I knew I'd be stuck here.
Nero!
Stop being unreasonable.
Are you having an attack of selfishness?
Me and your dad are doing
something more important here
than what you want.
You better grow up, and while you're at it,
check your privileges as well.
Stop acting like the world
is revolving around you
and start being like your dad!
He's using his position to help others.
You're turning out to be
a big disappointment!
You're an embarrassment!
Are you really not feeling well?
No.
If you were bored earlier, Nero,
you should've just told us
instead of making up excuses.
I'm sorry, Dad.
I appreciate what you're doing,
but it's Tristan's birthday,
and there's a big party in the mansion.
Like what I said, son,
you should've just told me.
I'll let you go to Tristan's party.
You will, Dad, but how about Mom?
She is expecting me to be like you,
that's why I need to be on your tail always.
The last time I asked permission from her,
she made me feel that
I was just wasting my time.
Instead of me enjoying time with my friends,
I should just help others
and join you in your medical missions.
Dad, I'm proud of what you're doing,
but sometimes,
I just want to be a normal teenager.
To be a Ferell and enjoy with my cousins
with grandpa.
Don't worry, I'll talk to your mom.
Maybe it's better if we don't bring you along
to our activities.
You can still join us
if you feel like joining us...
but you don't have to go with me and your mom
to our outreach programs
and medical missions.
Dad!
Eliza, don't blame Nero for what happened.
I need some time alone, Papa.
I need time to process all these things
that are happening to me.
I hope you understand.
Well, if that's what you want,
I won't stop you.
Please take care of Nero.
I'll come back once I'm ready to face him.
I failed, Florence.
I failed to heal my grandson.
This is all my fault.
I should've been a better grandpa.
You know what, Grandpa Garp?
One of the things my mother taught me is...
that the most powerful cure for pain is time,
because if the days become a month,
and months turn into years,
no matter how deep,
the pain and wounds will heal.
You know, your mother is right.
And thank you so much, Florence.
You reminded me not to lose hope.
More chopsuey?
Florence, what's for breakfast?
There, it's right in front of you.
It will bite you.
Don't you have eyes?
You're so grouchy this early.
Happy morning, Troy and Owen.
I made you some juice,
coffee, or hot chocolate.
What do you want to drink?
We're okay with the orange juice.
Thank you, Florence.
- Thank you.
- Wait, why is there favoritism here?
With Troy and Owen, you're sweet,
- but to Tristan and me, you're grouchy.
- That's true.
Maybe you're not nice.
Do we have to be nice?
I pity you.
What's your problem?
Hey, let me just flex that these two guys
are the sweetest to me in the mansion so...
We're sweet too.
In your face.
Let's go and eat.
Attack!
Where is Nero?
He's having an attack of mood swings.
Is he a weirdo again for today?
It's actually his dad's birthday...
so we should be extra careful with him today.
Or better yet, no one should go near him.
Let him be by himself.
Florence, you called. Do you have a problem?
What's with you?
She just called and you're thinking
there's a problem right away.
Maybe she's just checking on us.
Father, I don't always call
because I have a problem.
But now, Father, I do have a small problem.
Just a small one.
Did someone insult you?
Are you feeling down?
Do you have an existential crisis
that you're going through?
Father is overreacting.
I'm having problems
because there's a fruit that I need
but it's not in season.
What's that?
This house is so far.
What is this house?
My God.
I think I'll have a heart attack.
I'm feeling dizzy...
- Dizzy.
- It feels like I lost weight.
I have a feeling I became sexy.
Hey, you look as if
you really saw someone sexy.
Look at you. You're so naughty. Naughty...
Mother! Father!
- Dear!
- Oh, Florence!
Father!
I missed you.
Hey, you look thin.
Wait, why are you out of your room
with incomplete clothing?
Father, that's how things are here.
But Father, you look handsome.
You know Mother, if I didn't know Father,
I would say having a heart disease
suits him well.
Hey, Florencia!
I'm sorry, Mother. It's just a joke.
Your mother doesn't really
have a sense of humor.
You shouldn't be making a joke
about heart disease.
Father, Mother is right.
Bad joke... bad joke, Florencia!
I'm sorry, Mother. I just miss you,
and I'm happy that I saw you again.
I also miss you, Florence.
We miss you so much at home.
If you only know.
I always catch your mother
staring at your picture, crying.
You're something else.
Anyway, Florence,
here's the thing you asked us to buy.
Is that enough?
This is perfect, Mother.
Thank you, Mother.
Mother, why don't you come in first?
No, thank you.
Are you sure? Even for a while?
I still have to make her walk.
Maybe there's a chance she can become sexy.
- Hey, you!
- Mother is sexy.
You better go in because you might get sick.
- Okay. Take care.
- You better dress properly.
Wear something...
- Take care.
- Okay, take care, my child.
- I love you, Florence.
- I love you, Mother, Father!
I love you. Love you, Florence!
Operation Rambutan commences.
You know what?
You're so beautiful.
You look like Gretchen Barretto so much.
Especially with this side view
and in the dark.
Thank you.
I'll take that as a compliment.
What's with you?
Don't take it as a compliment.
Take it as a supplement
so that it's more nutritious.
You're something else.
You always make me laugh.
Why?
Can you sense danger?
It seems there's a different smell.
Hey.
Serafica, I took a bath.
And after I took a bath,
I scrubbed using fabric conditioner
with perfume collection.
No, there's really a different scent.
I can't smell anything.
I'm sure there's a new scent.
It's faint smell and it seems like...
there's something different in the kitchen.
I should know because I spent years here,
that's why I know
if there's a new scent or what.
Oh, I know it already.
Maybe you can smell...
the warmth of my love.
I agree.
The scent is so strong,
and you have a good and genuine character.
Really?
Serafica?
Let's leave this place now.
We might get the kitchen dirty,
with our burning feelings.
I'll go with you.
Let's go.
You're something else. Stop it!
Where's the switch?
Here.
Why is there none?
Why is it here?
Switch at the back? Really?
It seems it's going to explode.
In fairness.
Hey you, don't be noisy.
You act as if I'm a stranger to you
though you go to me every morning
to send messages.
You're surprised? I know your boss' secret.
Maybe he thinks,
he's the only one capable of
sending those secret messages.
If he's sending secret messages,
then I have secret fruit, rambutan.
You look handsome up front, Mr. Ferell.
Nero got his looks from you.
But you know, you raised Nero very well.
He's a good person.
He's been secretly kind to me.
I thought at first he was so grouchy to me.
Don't touch any part of my car.
It turns out he's not.
He is hurting because of your passing.
I have a little favor to ask you.
Can you visit Nero?
But don't scare him off.
Just visit him in his dreams,
and then tell him that...
there are people who care for him.
Especially Grandpa Garp and me too,
even slightly...
I care for Nero.
See, I have some rambutan for you.
I hope Nero will like it.
I already said a lot of things.
I'll go ahead.
He shouldn't catch me here, so it's a secret.
The doves.
Hey, hey, get out! Get out of there.
This way.
Come here. Hurry. Get out.
They don't want to go out. Go, go, go.
Hey! There. Are there any doves left?
You two get out. Let's go.
Let's go.
The picture.
Hurry! The fire is getting bigger!
Hurry!
- Call the firemen!
- Move back!
Move back!
- Water, water!
- It's getting near.
- Water!
- It's getting near!
Did anyone bring a phone?
- We need a phone!
- Call the fire department!
Move away!
- There's no more water!
- Did anyone bring a phone?
What happened to my cabin?
- Hey!
- Nero, Nero!
- My things! Let go of me!
- Hey! Nero, Nero, Nero!
My things!
- There's nothing we can do.
- You don't understand.
- My things are important to me!
- Keep him away!
My cabin!
- It's dangerous!
- Wait! My things!
- My things! Let go of me!
- Stop it, Nero!
Wait.
You don't understand! I need my things!
It's dangerous!
- Stop it, Nero!
- Nero, that's enough!
- That's enough!
- Stop it!
That's enough!
Why do you have this?
What are you doing here?
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean it.
All of a sudden, there was a fire.
Nero... just calm down.
Let's find out first what happened.
Maybe all of this was just an accident.
This woman destroyed a place
that's very important to me.
How can I calm down?
Tell me how can I calm down?
I'm sure Florence didn't mean to do this.
Hey Owen, stop it first.
It's not the time to take sides.
What Owen is saying is
don't jump to conclusions.
Maybe Florence has an explanation for this.
You too.
Stop it! Everyone should stop,
and please, everyone, inside!
Do you think Nero will forgive her?
I don't think so, because knowing Nero,
he's one of the toughest people that I know.
Knowing Florence,
she can be quite persuasive.
Let's make a bet.
Owen and I will make a bet.
Game.
[Forgiveness is an expensive gift.
Not everyone deserves it.]
Nero?
You owe me three P's.
Human Development Program of the government?
I meant, you owe me three favors.
What kind of favor?
Any.
As in any favor?
Yes.